<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="design_overview">

	<title>Architecture</title>

	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;
		is based on robust and proven &THIS.PLATFORM;
		JAIN SLEE 1.1 Server and &THIS.PLATFORM;
		jSS7 Stack and provides easy integration with any third party communication protocol and platform.
	</para>

	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM;
		JAIN SLEE Server is a highly scalable event-driven application server with a robust component model and fault tolerant execution environment. It provides a set of connectors to a
		variety of networks elements: SS7 MAP, TCAP, INAP, ISUP, SMPP, XMPP, SIP, MGCP, HTTP, XDM, XCAP, Diameter and many others. It is fully compliant with JSR 240 (JSLEE 1.1).
	</para>

	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM;
		jSS7 is a software based implementation of the SS7 protocol. It provides implementation for Level 2 and above in the SS7 protocol Stack. &THIS.PLATFORM;
		jSS7 Stack User Guide is bundled within and you can refer to the guide for more details on the Stack.
	</para>

	<para>The diagram below depicts a high level design of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;.</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/smsc-application-design-overview.png" format="PNG" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.APPLICATION;
				Design overview
			</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; provides four basic services of an SMSC as shown in the figure above. Each of these four services are implemented in the Gateway as a module that can be activated or deactivated based on the needs of an operator. All these services interact with the Cassandra database for storing data (messages not yet sent and an archive for sent/failed to send messages) and retreiving data for messages that are pending to be sent.
	</para>
	<para>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Service Modules</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Mo (Mobile originated) module</term>
				<listitem><para>Handles mobile originated SMS.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Mt (Mobile terminated)</term>
				<listitem><para>Delivers SMS to mobile.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Rx SMPP module</term>
				<listitem><para>Listens for incoming SMS from ESME and routes them to Mt module.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Tx SMPP module
</term>
				<listitem><para>Listens for SMS from Mo module and delivers them to ESME over
SMPP.
</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Administration</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>CLI
					</term>
					<listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; comes with a Command Line Interface (CLI) that provides easy to use commands to manage and monitor the SS7 Stack and the SMSC Gateway.
					</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Web Interface
					</term>
					<listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; also includes an easy to use Web Interface administration tool that allows you to manage and monitor the Gateway via a convenient Web console.
					</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Campaign Tool
					</term>
					<listitem><para>In addition, future releases will also offer a Web based campaign tool to define and manage campaigns.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</para>

	

</chapter>

