<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="overview">

    <title>Overview </title>
        <section id="smsc_gateway_desc">
            <title>SMSC Gateway</title>
            <para>SMSC (Short Message Service Center) is a telecommunications network facility responsible for handling the SMS operations of a wireless network. When a subscriber sends an SMS message from a mobile phone, the message first reaches the SMS Center which then forwards the message to the desired destination. The SMS Center is responsible for routing the SMS messages and regulating the process. If the recipient is not reachable (the phone is switched off or out of coverage area etc.) the SMS Center will store the message and forward it to the recipient when available. </para>
        </section>
    <section id="telscale_smsc_overview">
        <title>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;</title>
       <para>&THIS.PLATFORM;'s implementation of SMSC Gateway is the first and only open source SMSC Gateway with a host of rich features and advantages.
            </para>
<para>
            <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Java-based:</term>
                    <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is the only Java based SMSC Gateway. It is robust and reliable and can be installed on any Operating System that supports Java (JDK 7 and SCTP).</para></listitem>
                </varlistentry>               
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Open Source:</term>
                    <listitem><para>The Software is open-source, giving you the freedom the understand the code and customise it to your enterprise needs. It is supported by a vibrant Open source community.</para></listitem>
                </varlistentry>   
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>SS7 Hardware Cards:</term>
                    <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; supports E1/T1 links via SS7 cards (Dialogic SS7 cards) or Zaptel/Dahdi compatible TDM devices (Digium, Sangoma).</para></listitem>
                </varlistentry>     
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>SIGTRAN (M3UA):</term>
                    <listitem><para>It also supports connectivity to MSC/HLR via SIGTRAN links (M3UA using SCTP).</para></listitem>
                </varlistentry>  
 		 <varlistentry>
                    <term>Cloud-ready:</term>
                    <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is cloud-ready and can also be deployed on a private cloud infrastructure.</para></listitem>
                </varlistentry>               
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Easy Configuration and Management:</term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; comes with an efficient Command Line Interface (CLI) tool allowing you to easily configure the gateway at run-time and manage it using
                            simple commands rather than do everything manually. Future releases will include an efficient Web Interface administration tool for easy management and monitoring through a Web console. In addition there will also be a Web based campaign tool to define and manage campaigns.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>               
              <!--  <varlistentry>
                    <term>Technical Specifications:</term>
                    <listitem> <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is not restricted by any license or Transaction Per Second model. The only restricting factor is memory + CPU capacity of the host servers,
                        third-party applications or the underlying database service.
                        <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; supports as many as 1073741823 incoming and 1073741823 outgoing concurrent sessions/dialogs.</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; supports unlimited E1 links and the only limiting factor is the underlying TDM board used.</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; SCTP supports as many associations as supported by the underlying Operating System.</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; M3UA can be confgured to have as many ASP's / IPSP's as needed by the system.</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; SCCP can be confgured to have virtually unlimited Global Title Translation rules and also supports wild characters for partial matching of Global Title digits.</para></listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>       
                    </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>    -->                                                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Major Features:</term>
                    <listitem> <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; enables mobile operators to provide core SMSC features like subscriber to subscriber SMS messaging, broadcasting campaigns and group messaging between subscribers.
			<itemizedlist> 
				<listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; can handle mobile originated SMS and deliver to the intended recipient. It also provides a flexible routing mechanism to route messages to ESME over SMPP protocol.</para></listitem> 
				<listitem><para>Additionally, when enabled with proper administrator privileges, &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; allows convenient group messaging between subscribers (e.g. family, friends, colleagues) .</para></listitem> 
				<!--<listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; offers “SMS Broadcasting” which enables marketing campaigns. Via
convenient Web UI, campaign administrators can prioritize, schedule and monitor a
message broadcasting workfow. Campaigns can be distributed over multiple SMSC
instances for faster SMS delivery to all intended recipients.</para></listitem> -->

				<listitem><para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is built on the TelScale jSS7 stack which provides advanced SCCP routing
rules to map short codes to MSISDN, allowing users to send an SMS to a short-code instead of a complete MSISDN. </para></listitem>

				<listitem><para>It also enables value added services through integration with OTT social networks and microblogs such as Facebook and Twitter.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
A single &THIS.PLATFORM; SMSC node can process up to 1000 SMS/sec. Multiple SMSC nodes can be arranged in a cluster across one or more geographically distributed data centers to scale up throughput and provide various levels of redundancy, high availability and fault tolerance.
</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
                    </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>  
		 <varlistentry>
                    <listitem> <para>    &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; can be adapted to the needs of telecom service providers of different sizes in any country. 
   			</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>  
                                              
            </variablelist>   
	    </para>
        </section>

</chapter>


