<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="notes">
	<title>Important Notes</title>
   <!-- <section id="jss7_overview">
    	<title>Overview</title>-->
	<section id="notes_download">
		<title>Download</title>
		<para>
		The binary release is available for download from the TeleStax Customer Support Portal at <ulink url="&THIS.RELEASE_BINARY_URL;" />.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_whats_included">
		<title>What's Included?</title>
		<para>
		This binary release includes: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>cassandra: Contains the script for creating the Cassandra Keyspace.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>docs: Contains all relevant documentation in respective subfolders.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>jboss-5.1.0.GA: The core server with two profiles "default" and "simulator". The "default" profile is a clean profile where you will have to start from scratch and configure the entire SS7 Stack and SMSC Gateway. The "simulator" profile is a pre-configured profile to work with jss7-simulator. Refer to the Admin Guide for instructions on how to start the server in either of the profiles.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>resources: Contains SLEE MAP RA jars.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>tools: Contains SLEE tools and jss7-simulator.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_whats_new">
		<title>What's New?</title>
		<formalpara>
		<title>New Database Schema</title>
		<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; comes with a new Database Schema. The procedure to create the database has been changed and is explained in the Installation Guide. The &THIS.APPLICATION; creates three tables for every new day with the date suffixed to the names of the tables as <literal>DST_SLOT_TABLE_yyyy_mm_dd</literal>, <literal>SLOT_MESSAGES_TABLE_yyyy_mm_dd</literal> and <literal>MESSAGES_yyyy_mm_dd</literal> where <literal>yyyy_mm_dd</literal> is the date in that format. Refer to the Admin Guide for more details on the database structure.
		</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara>
		<title>Support for SMS Home Routing</title>
		<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; supports SMS Home Routing that enables you to handle Mobile Terminated messages in the network that owns the customer so you can offer a full range of advanced and value added services on both inbound and outbound SMS. You may switch on/off SMS Home Routing according to your requirements.</para> 
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara>
		<title>Monitoring SMSC Statistics</title>
		<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; now allows you to monitor the SMSC and view the current statistics in the GUI Management Console or through the Command Line Interface.
		</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara>
		<title>CDR for Receipt messages</title>
		<para>The SMSC can now be configured to generate CDR for both receipt and regular messages or generate CDR only for regular messages. For more details on how to configure this setting, please refer to the Admin Guide.
		</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara>
		<title>Additional SMSC Parameters</title>
		<para>You can now configure few additional SMSC Parameters (<literal>reviseSecondsOnSmscStart</literal> and <literal>processingSmsSetTimeout</literal>) using CLI and GUI. 
		</para>
		</formalpara>
	</section>
	<section id="features_bug_fixes">
		<title>Issues Fixed</title>
		<para>For a full list of resolved issues please refer to <ulink url="https://bitbucket.org/telestax/telscale-smscgateway/issues?milestone=TelScale SMSC 6.1.5.GA" />.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Config_settings">
		<title>Configuration Settings</title>
		<para>You must perform post-installation configuration of the Gateway according to instructions in the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Admin Guide. Before using in Production, you must remember to fine-tune Memory, Database and logging settings for better performance.</para>
<warning><para>Failure to configure memory, database, logging and other settings as per the instructions in the Admin Guide may result in poor performance of the Gateway.</para></warning>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_doc">
		<title>Documentation</title>
		<para>
		When you download the binary release and extract the contents of the zip file, you will notice that the top level directory is named <literal>telscale-smsc-&lt;version&gt;</literal> and within the <literal>telscale-smsc-&lt;version&gt;/docs</literal> folder you will find the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Installation Guide and Admin Guide. For installation and usage guidance, please refer to these guides that will help you to install and configure the Gateway.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_support">
		<title>Support</title>
		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is fully supported by TeleStax. For help with the software or to raise bugs please login to your account at <ulink url="https://telestax.zendesk.com/home" /> and follow the instructions.
		</para>
	</section>


		
</chapter>
