<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="notes">
	<title>Important Notes</title>
   <!-- <section id="jss7_overview">
    	<title>Overview</title>-->
	<section id="notes_download">
		<title>Download</title>
		<para>
		The binary release is available for download from the TeleStax Customer Support Portal at <ulink url="&THIS.RELEASE_BINARY_URL;" />.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_whats_included">
		<title>What's Included?</title>
		<para>
		This binary release includes: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>cassandra: Contains the script for creating the Cassandra Keyspace.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>docs: Contains all relevant documentation in respective subfolders.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>jboss-5.1.0.GA: The core server with two profiles "default" and "simulator". The "default" profile is a clean profile where you will have to start from scratch and configure the entire SS7 Stack and SMSC Gateway. The "simulator" profile is a pre-configured profile to work with jss7-simulator. Refer to the Admin Guide for instructions on how to start the server in either of the profiles.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>resources: Contains SLEE MAP RA jars.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>tools: Contains SLEE tools and jss7-simulator.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_whats_new">
		<title>What's New?</title>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Support for datagramm and transactional modes</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; now comes with support for SMPP datagramm and transactional modes. Previous versions supported only ForwardAndStore mode.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Forward and store mode</title>
        <para>A special "Forward and store" mode has been introduced for the purpose of process optimization. A user can configure the SMSC Gateway to have messages stored in the cassandra database only if an attempt to deliver fails the first time. This mode also enables delivering messages in the shortest time in the first attempt.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>GSM8 message encoding support</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; now comes with support for GSM8 encoding (Now all GSM7, GSM8 and UCS2 are supported).
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Latest version of TelScale JSS7 library and Datastax driver</title>
        <para>The latest TelScale JSS7 6.2.0 library and Datastax version are included in this release.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Processing statistics</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; introduces statistic counters for some key parameters. For example, number of messages received / sent. These statistics can now be observed in the GUI.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>X-headers for SIP message</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; can now process special X-headers for SIP messages that help in sending UDH to/from SIP etc.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>SMSC Pause Option</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; comes with a SMSC Pause Option. A user can pause message delivery (incoming storeAndForward messages will be stored in a database; incoming datagramm, transactional and forwardAndStore messages will be rejected).
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Message content stored in text format</title>
        <para>Message content is now stored in text format in the database field "MESSAGE_TEXT" (UDH is kept in binary form in a separate database field).
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Command Line SMPP Load Testing Tool</title>
        <para>A new Command line load testing tool is now available for generating SMPP traffic, just like HLR simulator.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>TON_NATIONAL Support</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; accepts TypeOfNumber as 'TON_NATIONAL'.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
        <formalpara>
	<title>Process throttling SMPP responses</title>
	<para>In datagramm, transactional and FAS modes the SMSC will send throttling SMPP responses when throttling problems occur. The smpp-load Client will now appropriately process them and resend requests to SMSC.
	</para>
        </formalpara>
	<formalpara>
	<title>Null Password for ESME definition
	</title>
	<para>While defining ESME, Password can be null.	
	</para>
	</formalpara>
        <formalpara>
        <title>Additional configuration</title>
        <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; has additional configuration options. For example, storing records into CDR's and archive database tables, rejecting all incoming SS7 originated messages, etc.
        </para>
        </formalpara>
	</section>
	<section id="features_bug_fixes">
		<title>Issues Fixed</title>
		<para>For a full list of resolved issues and their details, please refer to <ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC/" />.</para>	
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC-130">SMSC-130</ulink>: RsdsSbb errors when InvokeTimeout, ComponentError
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC-151">SMSC-151</ulink>: CDR Timestamp format not uniform
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC-112">SMSC-112</ulink>: submit_sm with validity fails
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC-134">SMSC-134</ulink>: SMPP Client mode (from SMSC side) does not work properly
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC-135">SMSC-135</ulink>: Concurrent SMPP bind request from multiple ESME's uses same esme definition from SMSC
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://telestax.atlassian.net/browse/SMSC-161">SMSC-161</ulink>: Double messages in SIP->SMSC messageflow
</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section id="Config_settings">
		<title>Configuration Settings</title>
		<para>You must perform post-installation configuration of the Gateway according to instructions in the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Admin Guide. Before using in Production, you must remember to fine-tune Memory, Database and logging settings for better performance.</para>
<warning><para>Failure to configure memory, database, logging and other settings as per the instructions in the Admin Guide may result in poor performance of the Gateway.</para></warning>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_doc">
		<title>Documentation</title>
		<para>
		When you download the binary release and extract the contents of the zip file, you will notice that the top level directory is named <literal>telscale-smsc-&lt;version&gt;</literal> and within the <literal>telscale-smsc-&lt;version&gt;/docs</literal> folder you will find the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Installation Guide and Admin Guide. For installation and usage guidance, please refer to these guides that will help you to install and configure the Gateway.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_support">
		<title>Support</title>
		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is fully supported by TeleStax. For help with the software or to raise bugs please login to your account at <ulink url="https://telestax.zendesk.com/home" /> and follow the instructions.
		</para>
	</section>


		
</chapter>
